<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Marc Wiedermann</title>
    <link>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Marc Wiedermann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 11:16:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcwie.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Scatter Plots with d3.js</title>
      <link>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/responsive-scatter-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 11:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/responsive-scatter-d3/</guid>
      <description>I continued with dusting off my d3.js -skills. After revisiting how to draw responsive bar charts, I continued to address the second out of five d3.js coding challenges from freecodecamp&amp;rsquo;s course on data visualization . The purpose of this challenge is to create a responsive scatter plot of the 35 fastest bicycle riders to finish the climb up to Alpe d’Huez and indicate whether they were later confronted with doping allegations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial infographics in python using cartopy and shapely #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/spatial-infographics-cartopy-shapely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 20:17:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/spatial-infographics-cartopy-shapely/</guid>
      <description>Ever since matplotlib&amp;rsquo;s basemap has been deprecated I wanted to take a closer look at the cartopy project so that I can keep using python for displaying data on maps. Fortunately, this week&amp;rsquo;s #tidytuesday project concerns spatially explicit data of African water sources provided by Water Point Data Exchange. The data is provided as a csv table which, among others, contains the longitudinal and latitudinal position of a water source as well as its type (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Include code from external file in a hugo blog post</title>
      <link>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/external-text-hugo-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:46:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/external-text-hugo-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>I am creating my personal webpage (i.e., this site) with hugo and sometimes include code blocks (e.g., javascript) into my posts. One obvious way to achieve this is copying the code directly into the corresponding markdown file. However, since I may adjust this code in the future but still want my blog post to show the most recent version, I was looking for a solution that allows me to import the code as a block of text into the markdown file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a responsive Bar Chart with d3.js</title>
      <link>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/responsive-bar-chart-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 20:25:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcwie.github.io/blog/responsive-bar-chart-d3/</guid>
      <description>For a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to dust off my skills in creating responsive graphics with d3.js. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve used it to create some visualizations of complex networks or simple interactive dashboards for my former clients.
I went back to freecodecamp&amp;rsquo;s course on data visualization which provides a highly recommended introduction to d3 for all those with some experience in web development, i.e., html, css and javascript. Below is my implementation of their first out of five Coding Challenges that visualizes a time series of quarterly US GDP with a bar chart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
